## SAI BHASKER RAJU CHITTAPRAGADA

<u>schittap@uwo.ca</u> <u>|saibhaskerraju@outlook.com</u> |+1-(226)-998-4770 | Unit 60, 70 Chapman Court, London, ON, Canada http://saibhaskerraju.tk | https://www.linkedin.com/in/saibhaskerraju/ |https://github.com/uwobhaskerraju

# **Professional Summary:**

Professional with over 3 years of working experience involved in all phases of software development seeking to combine practical experience in a dynamic IT environment; posses a strong background in software development, databases and Microsoft's Technology Stack.

#### Education:

Master of Engineering – Software Engineering

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020

The University of Western Ontario, London, ON, CA

GPA - current

Concentration: Full Stack Web Development (Angular 8, Node.js, MongoDB) and Data Analytics

**MEng Project:** Empire Hut is a web application built for people to buy/sell property in a secured and decentralized way. It leverages the power of Ethereum blockchain to make it secure and tamper proof. This application tracks your assets and transactions, allows users to buy/sell property in minutes by eliminating paperwork, middlemen and costs, for a small transaction fee.

### **Professional Experience:**

# Cognizant Technology Solutions - Hyderabad, India

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019

**Programmer Analyst** 

Developed REST APIs for "TheFA - Matchday" using C# and deployed to Azure API Management Portal for end users to consume without any latency.

- Developed APIs to show LIVE status of matches to keep users posted
- Developed APIs to display payment dues of players for signed up matches
- Worked on security improvements of authorization and authentication REST APIs
- Implemented design patterns to maintain code re-usability and maintainability

Environment: C#.NET, Azure Logic Apps and Azure API Management

## Prolifics Corporation - Hyderabad, India

July 2016 - Oct 2018

Associate Software Engineer

Created SSIS Packages for Hudson Advisors for their daily ETL Operations, efficiently loaded high volume data per day and gracefully handled errors to manage failures.

- Revamped the existing logic to import huge unstructured excel sheet data into database using C# and Spreadsheet Gear to streamline overall data loading process and error logging
- Migrated on-premise applications and data-loading operations into Azure SQL Warehouse and Amazon Redshift leveraging the power of cloud to speed up the ETL process
- Earned "RACE" award twice for outstanding performance in data migration project from on-premise to Azure
- Accelerated the data loading process by using In-Memory Tables as stage tables in SQL Server
- Reduced deployment time to 5 minutes from 20min by automating the continuous integration process using PowerShell scripts

Environment: C#.NET, Azure Logic Apps, Azure SQL Datawarehouse, PowerShell, SSIS, SQL Server, S3 Bucket and Amazon Redshift

### **Voluntary Experience:**

#### Microsoft Student Partner

Jan 2020 - Current | March 2015 - April 2016

Student Trainer and Campus Ambassador

• Delivered hands-on training sessions in my college to enable students on fundamentals of Azure. These activities were part of Azure Learning to empower students on latest technologies

### Firefox Student Ambassador

March 2015 - April 2016

Student Trainer and Campus Ambassador

- Trained students on Web technologies like HTML5, CSS3, JS by starting in-class training sessions
- Launched a programming club in my college to build and start a developer community that builds apps for a better future

# **Certifications:**